会有多疼啊
How much will it hurt?
只是一块小小皮肤样本
It's just a tiny skin sample.
你也看过我给自己取样本的样子了
You saw me do it to myself.
疼痛程度按1到10分
On a scale of one to ten,
1分是鞋子里进石子
where one is a pebble in your shoe
10分是你以为是爱宠的猴子
and ten is the monkey you thought
正在啃掉你脸的疼痛度
was your pet biting your face off.
2分
A two.
吃超超凉薄荷糖的程度吗
Eating a whole Altoid?
要想我通过我们的皮肤细胞
Sheldon, if I'm gonna synthesize a neural network
来合成出神经网络  我就得先采集材料啊
from our skin cells, I need to harvest them.
我取样本已经驾轻就熟了
Now, I've done this dozens of times,
但如果你要是怕  也不用勉强
but if you're too scared you don't have to.
不行  这是为了科学
No, this is for science.
我可以为科学而勇敢
I can be brave for science.
谢谢啊
Thank you.
我擦  好冰啊
Oh, jiminy, that's cold!
你就想着几周后
Just think how happy you'll be in a few weeks
当我把我们的皮肤细胞
when I've converted our skin cells
转化为功能性脑细胞时  你会多开心
into functional brain cells.
好吧  那你下手前一定要先提醒我
All right, just warn me before you do it.
好
Okay.
三
Three...
二...  搞定啦
two... and we're done.
你骗了我
You tricked me.
你没喊一
You didn't say one.
-那也不疼啊  不是吗  -是不疼...
- It didn't hurt, did it? - No...
但"三  二  搞定啦"不完整啊
but "Three, two and we're done" is incomplete.
你明知道这样会让我很闹心
You know those things bother me.
就像是听到...
It's like hearing "Da-da-da-da-da-dah"
而不接着喊出...
without yelling...
服了你  行  一
Okay, fine, one.
谢谢
Thank you.
现在大喊"冲啊"  我们就可以杀出去了
Now yell "Charge" and we can get out of here.
该旋律《Charge》曾在球赛
与卡通《摩登原始人》中出现而闻名
天啊  我现在懂了
Oh, my God, I just got it.
有趣的洋葱圈
Fun onions...
趣葱圈
Funyuns.
等等
Hold on.
是摆动吗
Is that a wobble?
是呢
Yes.
绝对是个引力摆动
That's definitely a gravitational wobble.
抱歉打扰了  我等下再过来吧
Uh, sorry, I could come back.
没事的
Oh, no, it's okay.
我刚才发现了一个摆动[有点滑]
I-I just found a wobble.
需要我去拿拖把吗
Oh, do I need a mop?
是引力摆动
It's a gravitational wobble.
这表示有可能发现了一颗
It could be a sign of an extrasolar planet
蕴涵有生命的系外行星  某天会以我名字而命名呢
that may contain life and someday be named after me.
如果上面已经有生命了
Oh... well, if it has life,
那它估计已经有名字了吧
maybe it already has a name, huh?
的确  但有可能对我们来说很难发音
Yeah, but it's probably difficult to pronounce.
你叫什么名字
What is your name?
拉杰什·罗摩衍·库萨帕里
Rajesh Ramayan Koothrappali.
你觉得能比这个还难念吗
You think it would be more difficult than that?
有道理
Good point.
小姐芳名
And you are?
伊莎贝拉·玛丽亚·康赛普西翁
Oh, uh, Issabella Maria Concepcion.
很高兴认识你
Oh, well, nice to meet you.
我也是
Nice to meet you, too.
我不得不说
You know, I have to say,
从垃圾桶里的糖果包装纸
based on the candy wrappers
还有垃圾食品的包装袋来看
and the bags of junk food I see in this trash,
我本来以为在这里工作的人是个十岁小孩呢
I thought the person working here was ten years old.
拜托  世上哪里有十岁就懂
Oh, please, show me a ten-year-old who knows
拿巧克力棒沾巧克力酱的孩子啊
to dip Tootsie Rolls in Nutella.
好啦  我清空一下你的废纸篓
Bueno, um, I'm just going to empty your waste paper basket
然后我就不打扰你了
and then I'll get out of your way.
放着我来
Oh, please, allow me.
好多的无营养热量啊
That's a lot of empty calories.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
好了  我该走了
Okay, uh, okay, I-I-I have to go.
祝你的太空探索好运啦
Good luck with your, um, space exploration.
谢谢
Thank you.
也祝你...
Good luck with your...
万事如意
future endeavors.
成功了吗
Did it work?
变成大脑细胞了吗
Are they brain cells yet?
你安静等我一会  我就能回答你了
If you'd give me a minute, I'll tell you.
让我自己来看
Oh, just let me look.
我的老天爷啊
Oh, my goodness!
我看到颤抖的黑线了
I see quivering black lines.
那些肯定是神经元
Those must be neurons.
它们又粗又充满美感
Oh, they're so thick and beautiful.
那是你的眼睫毛  让开
Those are your eyelashes, move.
谢尔顿
Well, Sheldon...
我看到了星形胶质细胞
I see astrocytes.
我们皮肤细胞的结合现在是原始的神经网络了
Our combined skin cells are now a primitive neural network.
我内心有无比深刻的造物感
I have such a profound sense of creation.
就像小时候孵化海猴子一样
I ju... it's like when I hatched Sea-Monkeys,
曾流行过的儿童养殖玩具  把卵加入水中
即可孵出丰年虾[海猴]
但这个是用我DNA创造的
except that this is from my DNA,
所以简直就像是...
so this is like...
我猴
Me-Monkeys.
这些细胞我们俩人的共同产物
These cells come from both of us.
但是"我们的猴"听起来就不带劲儿啊
Yeah, but Us-Monkeys doesn't pop.
等等  等等
Oh, oh, oh, oh, wait!
咱们猴  这下满意了吧
We-Monkeys, there you go.
我们可以开始在它们身上做实验了吗
When can we start running tests on it?
当然可以现在动手啦
No reason we can't start right now.
我们该先用什么刺激它呢
What stimulus should we introduce it to first?
光  声音  温度
L-Light, sound, temperature...
不如给它看我和你的照片
Let's expose it to images of me and you
看看它更喜欢谁
and see who it likes better.
谢尔顿  这只是一个未成熟的神经元组
Sheldon, this is a rudimentary collection of neurons.
虽然很了不起
I mean, it's remarkable,
但它能做的事还是很有限
but it's still limited in what it can do.
明白
I understand.
妈妈凶巴巴  爸爸笑哈哈
She's the mean one, I'm the fun one.
餐厅搞错了  给我们放了清蒸西兰花
Huh, they screwed up and gave us steamed broccoli.
没错  那是我的
Oh, no, that's mine.
不是吧
Really?
我上次看到你吃绿色的东西是彩虹糖
The last green thing I saw you eat was a Skittle.
我的饮食不能总像一个十岁小孩吧
Well, I can't eat like a ten-year-old all the time.
你有对象了  说吧是谁
You're dating somebody, who is it?
什么
What?
你在胡说什么呀
What are you talking about?
你会注意饮食只有一个原因
You only watch what you eat when you're afraid
你害怕可能得在别人面前脱衣服
you might have to take your shirt off.
没错  她说得对
No, she's right.
自打我认识你以来
As long as I've known you,
你一直都很在意自己的乳沟
you've always been self-conscious about your cleavage.
那是因为你老想把铅笔夹里面
It's because you keep trying to stick pencils in it.
好吧  那行  别跟我们说
All right, fine, don't tell us.
-本来就没什么好说的  -好吧
- There's nothing to tell. - All right.
西兰花味道怎么样
How's that broccoli?
难吃又不得不吃  因为我有对象了
It's gross but I have to eat it because I met somebody.
看吧
Bam.
多谢
Thank you.
她叫什么
What's her name?
伊莎贝拉
Issabella.
你是在工作时认识她的吗
Oh, did you meet her at work?
是的  在观测室认识的
Yes, in the telescope room.
所以她是天文学家吗
Oh, so she's an astronomer?
是的
Yes...
不然她怎么会在观测室
which is why she was in the telescope room.
这就都说得通了  太好了
Yes, this is all making sense. Good.
不错嘛  拉杰
Well, that's great, Raj.
你们一定有很多共同点
You must have so much in common.
那我们什么时候能见见她
So, when do we meet her?
还不行  刚刚认识的
No, no, this is brand-new.
我们都没有正式约过会呢
We haven't even been on a proper date yet.
-好吧  那祝你好运  -谢谢
- Okay, well, good luck with it. - Thank you.
你怎么从来不吃西兰花
How come you never eat broccoli?
我都结婚了
I'm married,
不需要注意形象
I don't have to be attractive.
大多人都不知道这项技术
You know, most people don't realize this technique
其实好几年前就有了
has actually been around for a few years.
可我仍不敢相信你能把普通的皮肤细胞
Still, I can't believe you can turn ordinary skin cells
变成功能性脑细胞
into functioning brain cells.
我把这木头变成了功能完备的男友
Well, I turned this one into a functioning boyfriend,
所以世上无事不可为
so sky's the limit.
快看快看  这就是我
Look, look... here I am
站在细胞培养器旁边
standing next to the incubator.
这是显微镜下细胞的样子
Uh, here is a microscopic view of the cells.
瞧瞧  给它们穿一件小闪电侠T恤
Look at that, put them in a tiny Flash T-shirt
就长得跟你一样了
and it's you.
这个小家伙识别
Yeah, this little guy can already recognize
电子传输图像的速度
electronically transmitted images
已经比艾米实验室里所有样本都快20%
20% faster than any other sample in Amy's lab.
我已经没办法继续假装对此兴奋了
I'm running out of ways to act excited.
不说我们了  你最近怎么样
So, enough about us, how are things going with you?
非常好  医生说宝宝现在头朝下了
Great, the doctor said the baby's head is facing down now.
那就好
Good, you know,
以防出口不明显  找不到
in case the exit isn't clearly marked.
是啊  我必须要说能跟
Yeah, I have to say, it is nice to share
有相同进程的人分享这种体验  感觉真好
this experience with someone who's on the same journey.
虽然现在我们这个测试结果棒棒哒
Although right now ours is testing off the charts
而你的那个正泡在自己的排泄物里
while yours is floating around in its own waste.
你真的要拿我的人类宝宝
Are you actually comparing my human baby
跟你装在器皿里的脑细胞比吗
to your brain in a bowl?
不然你以为我让你
Well, I didn't make you waddle up
辛苦爬四层楼上来是为了什么
four flights of stairs for the heck of it.
你知道我宝宝有功能完备的器官
You do realize my baby has functioning organs
还能识别声音吧
and can recognize voices.
知道啊  但我们的可以在背景噪音中
Yeah, but ours can recognize a specific data stream
识别出特定的数据流
among background noise.
我的有发育完全的免疫系统
Mine has a fully developed immune system.
我们的不需要免疫系统
Ours doesn't need an immune system
因为它住在先进的德国制细胞培养器里
because it lives in a state-of-the-art German incubator.
谢尔顿  别说了
Sheldon, that's enough.
不要  好吧
Oh, yeah, no, fine.
我们不如承认两个作品
Let's just agree that both creations
都有各自独特的地方
are special in their own way
试图对比这两者是愚蠢的行为
and it is foolish to try and compare them.
然而我们的作品不需要靠跟霍华德上床才有
Although, we didn't need to have sex with Howard for ours,
所以还是我们赢
so we win.
这真有意思
This is fun.
我这辈子从没刷过马桶
I have never cleaned a toilet before.
你在开玩笑吧
You're kidding.
没有  从小就有一屋子佣人伺候我
No, I grew up with a house full of servants
现在我也有清洁阿姨
and now I have a cleaning lady...
她是一个很好的女人
...who is a lovely woman
我非常尊敬她
who I have great respect for.
没关系  你可以有清洁阿姨啊
It's okay, you're allowed to have a cleaning lady.
那就好  因为她还帮我遛狗
Oh, good, because she also walks my dog,
帮我买日用品  帮我剪头发
buys my groceries and cuts my hair.
我觉得她的工作叫妈妈
I think that's called a mommy.
原谅我..
So, forgive me...
八卦一下
forgive me for being nosy,
不过你那漂亮的橡胶手套下
but is-is there a wedding ring
有没有藏着一枚婚戒
under those pretty rubber gloves?
没有  已经不戴很多年了
No, not for many years.
所以你无拘无束吗
Oh, so, you are unencumbered?
我和我儿子过
Just me and my son.
我最爱孩子了  他多大
I love kids, how old is he?
十九岁
Nineteen.
这个年纪可爱
That's a cute age.
已经会干很多事了
They can do so many things.
他在加州大学洛杉矶分校上学  要当律师
He's studying to be a lawyer at UCLA.
太棒了
That's wonderful.
律师  我妹妹也是律师
A lawyer, my sister's a lawyer.
你瞧啊  我们有共同点了呢
Look at that, we have something in common.
大概是有吧
Yeah, I guess we do.
也许我们还有别的共同点呢
Maybe there are other things we have in common.
共同用餐时间  你爱吃饭吗
C-Come dinnertime, do you enjoy eating food?
拉杰什
Ay, Rajesh,
你是个好人  不过
I think you're very sweet, but
我要打两份工  没有时间约会
I work two jobs and I don't have time for dating.
当然了   我理解
Yeah, sure. I understand.
对  我也很忙的
Yeah, I'm very busy, too.
我真的不是针对你
Oh, please don't take it personal,
我觉得你是个非常好的男人
I think you're a very nice man.
我觉得你也很好
I think you're very nice as well.
谢谢你帮忙我干活
Thank you for helping me.
晚安  拉杰什
Good night, Rajesh.
好的
Oh, yes. Oh, okay.
晚安
Good night.
说不好
I don't know,
也许是除尿香饼气味闻嗨了
maybe it's the fumes from the urinal cakes,
可我觉得我们之间有点什么
but I feel like something is happening between us.
晚安  拉杰什
Good night, Rajesh.
好吧  我走
Okay. I'll leave.
我告诉你  每次我来到这里
But just know, every time I come in here,
都会想起你的
I'll be thinking of you.
你来看看这个
Would you look at that?
我们给它的画面带45%的白噪音
The image we gave it was 45% white noise,
可它还是完成了重建
and it still managed to reconstruct it.
我从来没看过这种结果
I've never seen results like this before.
我们回家的时候必须去买磁贴了
Yeah, we need to stop for magnets on the way home;
把这报告妥妥地吸冰箱上
this is going right on the fridge.
参与了这个高不高兴
Aren't you glad you participated in this?
高兴
Oh, I am.
你知道下一步该做什么吧
And you realize what the next step is?
培养第二份
Set up a second culture
尝试重复我们的结果
and try to replicate our results.
不是
Uh, no.
我们把那扇门锁好
We lock that door,
内裤往下拉  开始造个孩子
lower our underpants a little and make a baby.
造孩子  你在说什么
Make a baby? What are you talking about?
很明显  我们俩人的DNA结合无与伦比
Clearly the combination of our DNA is exceptional.
我们孩子也许是人类进化下一步的开端
Our child could be the next step in the evolution of mankind.
所有幼儿园都会任我们挑选
We... we'll be able to get into any preschool we want!
谢尔顿  我还没准备好要孩子
Sh-Sheldon, I'm not ready to have a baby.
你准备好了  我算着你的生理周期呢
Oh, yes, you are! I track your cycle.
在接下来的36小时内  你就像黑土地一样
For the next 36 hours you're as fertile
只要撒种啥都往出结
as a manure-covered wheat field.
我能清楚地感觉到
Wow. I-I can actually feel
我的卵子被吓得爬回卵巢了
the egg crawling its way back up.
我不懂了
I don't understand.
我以为你跟我生育子女会很高兴呢
I thought you'd be thrilled to procreate with me.
但不是现在
Not right now.
我明白了
Oh, I see what's happening here.
你在跟我玩欲擒故纵
You're playing hard to get.
我什么都没玩
I'm not playing anything.
我们今天不会造孩子的
We're not making a baby today.
好吧
Very well.
哎呦喂  瞧宝宝我笨手笨脚的
Oops, how clumsy of me.
你瞧好了  我来捡
You know what? Let me get that.
你去哪呀
Where are you going?
我...
I...
你到底看没看我的屁屁
Did you even look at my bottom?
欢迎
Welcome.
这是干什么
What is this?
你说你没时间出去吃饭
Oh, well, you said you didn't have time to go out for dinner,
所以我想  我们可以在这里吃
so I thought we could have one right here.
-拉杰什  -来嘛
- Oh, Rajesh... - Oh, come on!
我们是在观测室里
We're in the telescope room!
跟在星空下用餐是一样的
It'll be like dining under the stars.
你看到这两个0了吗
Y-You see this, uh, double zero?
等变成"01"时  说明星星在闪
When it says "01," That means it's twinkling.
有时候得等一会儿
Sometimes it takes a while.
拉杰什  这确实很让人动心
Rajesh, this is so sweet,
不过你也知道   我还在工作
but you... you know I'm working.
所以我已经把这里  还有整条走廊的
That's why I already cleaned up in here
所有房间  都打扫干净了
and all the other rooms in the hall.
这样我的确是有点空闲时间了
Well, I suppose that gives me a little time.
请坐吧
Oh, please sit!
我还给你做了你的家乡菜
I tried to cook you a meal from your homeland.
真的吗
Oh, really?
你做了古巴菜吗
You made Cuban food?
这就要看古巴有没有卖墨西哥菜了
That depends-- do they have Mexican food in Cuba?
他说"造个孩子"
Now, when he said "Make a baby""
有没有可能是用乐高玩具拼一个
is it possible he meant out of Legos?
不是  他说的很露骨
No. He was explicit.
多余又异常露骨
Needlessly and freakishly explicit.
他要孩子干嘛用
Why does he need a baby?
他自己不就全身没毛  外加一股爽身粉味吗
He's already hairless and smells like talcum powder.
你俩真的能生出什么
Could you two really have some sort of
超级聪明的孩子吗
super-intelligent child?
遗传是有影响
Well, there is a genetic component,
但并不能保证什么
but that doesn't guarantee anything.
没错  谢尔顿的老爸
That's true. Sheldon's father
曾经和仙人掌大吵一架
once picked a fight with a cactus.
但那只是他地球上的养父母
Yeah, but that's just his Earth parents.
我们对送他来地球的亲生爹妈一无所知
We don't know anything about the ones that sent him here.
至少知道他们够聪明  知道把他送走
Well, we know they were smart enough to send him away.
注意点  你们说的是我爱的
Hey, you're talking about the person I love
而且躲了三小时的男人
and have been avoiding for the past three hours.
有没搞错
Aw, man.
这下谢尔顿性福啦
Sheldon gonna get some.
无论二号门后面是什么噩梦
Well, have fun with whatever nightmare's
都祝你玩得愉快
behind door number two.
美人你好啊
Well, hello.
你好
Hello.
来杯白兰地如何
Would you care for a brandy?
还是算了
I don't think so.
真聪明  难喝死了
Good choice, it's disgusting.
谢尔顿  请你别再色诱我了
Sheldon, please stop trying to seduce me.
谁在色诱你了
Who's trying to seduce you?
工作一天后  我总是会听舒缓的爵士乐
After a long day I always turn on smooth jazz
并在大腿内侧喷上鹿麝香
and spray deer musk on my inner thighs.
就觉得这里的味道好像宠物乐园
I thought it smelled like a petting zoo in here.
有什么你想"宠爱"一番的吗
Anything you'd like to pet?
别碰我的头发  用了发胶
Not my hair. There's a lot of goop in it.
我真是受够了
Okay, I've had enough.
艾米  回来
Amy, come back.
我不会开生蚝[壮阳用]
I don't know how to open the oysters.
你刚来美国时
So, um, what surprised you the most
什么最让你吃惊
when you first came to America?
我想应该是为什么那么多人都在乎
Well, I suppose how much people care
奥普拉最喜欢什么
about Oprah's favorite things.
我当时也这样想
I thought that, too.
然后我买了第一台华夫饼机
But then I got my first waffle maker
从此再没质疑过她的推荐
and never questioned her again.
这个星期天我休息
You know, I do have some time off this Sunday
-如果你想...  -我看到你的车
- if you'd like to... - Hey! I saw your car...
抱歉  我打扰你们了吗
Oh, sorry. Am I interrupting?
没事  我要回去工作了
Uh... It's okay. Uh, I should get back to work.
你好  我是霍华德·沃罗威茨
Hi. Howard Wolowitz.
我是伊莎贝拉·康赛普西翁
Oh. Issabella Concepcion.
对  那个天文学家
Oh, yeah, the astronomer.
拉杰提到过你
Raj told us about you.
不要钱的卫生纸
Hey! Free toilet paper!
你跟他说我是天文学家吗
You told him I was an astronomer?
我懂
I understand.
-该走了  -请别走
- Time to go. - No, p-please don't.
没事  拉杰什  我是成年人
It's okay, Rajesh, I'm a grown woman.
我不必在以我为耻的男人身上浪费时间
I don't have to waste my time with someone who's embarrassed by me.
这个不用还了  对吗
I can keep this, right?
伊莎贝拉
Issabella!
伊莎贝拉  等等  听我解释
Issabella, wait, wait, let me explain.
如果我的工作让你觉得没面子
If you are embarrassed by what I do,
-你为什么要追我  -对不起
- why did you pursue me? - I'm sorry.
说实话  我以为我不介意你的工作
Honestly, I-I didn't think your job would bother me,
但看来我介意
but I guess it did.
我为自己感到羞愧
And I hate myself for that.
但我也有很多事
But there's a lot of things about me
会让你觉得很没面子
that would totally embarrass you.
我不信
I doubt that.
准备好以我为耻吧
Well, prepare to be mortified.
我嘴对嘴喂我的狗吃东西
I let my dog eat food out of my mouth,
不是因为它喜欢  而是因为我喜欢
not because she likes it but because I do.
还有  我知道蝴蝶很美
Also, I know they're pretty,
但我怕它们
but I'm scared of butterflies.
抱歉  我只是路过
Sorry, just passing through.
我想这是你推车上掉下来的
I think this fell off your cart.
拜托  你怎么说
Come on. What do you say?
让我补偿你吧
Let me make it up to you.
你很锲而不舍
You're very persistent.
我就会死皮赖脸这一招
It's my one move.
好吧
Okay.
这个周日晚  你可以带我去高级餐厅吃晚餐
This Sunday night, you may take me to dinner at a nice restaurant.
太好了  你想去哪家
Great. Where would you like to go?
你来选
Your choice.
如果你喜欢  可以吃巴基斯坦菜
It can be Pakistani food, if you like.
不好意思  我是印度人
Excuse me, but I'm Indian.
现在你明白我的感受了吧
And now you know how it feels.
那么  你的性趣有被挑起哪怕一点点吗
So, were you turned on even a little bit?
感觉就像加入了狗仔队的皮威赫曼在泡你
It was like being hit on by Rat Pack Pee-wee Herman.
不好意思  是说有吗
I'm sorry, is that a yes?
没有
No!
艾米
Amy,
我也不想这样
I didn't want it to come to this.
但你让我别无选择
But you have left me no choice
唯有献上人类已知的
but to employ the most passionate,
最热情最具有诱惑力的舞蹈
seductive dance known to man.
弗拉明戈舞
The flamenco.
老天爷  你神经病啊
For God's sake, you're ridiculous.
你们俩看得情欲高涨了  对吗
You guys are aroused, right?
差点就失守了
That was a close one.